Hear how it all began.
A Quiet Place: Day One is a horror, science fiction,
thriller film directed by Michael Sarnoski.
As New York City is invaded by alien creatures who hunt by sound,
a woman named Sam fights to survive with her cat.
Samira, played by Lupita Nyong'o.
Eric, played by Joseph Quinn.
Reuben, played by Alex Wolff.
Henri, played by Djimon Hounsou.
Zena, played by Eliane Umuhire.
Osahar, played by Takunda Khumalo.
A Quiet Place: Day One is a 2024 American apocalyptic horror film, written and directed
by Michael Sarnoski, based on a story he conceived with John Krasinski.
It is the third installment in the A Quiet Place film
series, and a prequel to the first two films.
The film stars Lupita Nyong'o as a terminally ill woman during the early stages of an invasion in
New York City by blind extraterrestrial creatures with an acute sense of hearing.
The supporting cast includes Joseph Quinn and Djimon Hounsou,
who reprises his role from A Quiet Place Part II.
Development on A Quiet Place: Day One began in November 2020,
with Jeff Nichols set to write and direct.
Despite a completed script, Nichols dropped out of the film in October 2021.
In January 2022, Sarnoski was announced to replace Nichols as writer and director; he was
approached by Krasinski because of his feature directorial debut Pig (2021).
Principal photography took place from February 2023
to April 2023 in London, England.
A Quiet Place: Day One premiered at the Tribeca Festival on June 26, 2024, and was
released in the United States by Paramount Pictures on June 28.
The film received generally positive reviews from critics and grossed
$262 million worldwide on a $67 million production budget.
The film explores themes of monster, escape, cat, alien, prequel.
The tone is uplifting and dark and thought_provoking.